Guide to the Yevgeny Yevtushenko Papers M1088
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Audiovisual Materials, Series 8.
  - 1. Iu. Dombrovskii i dr.; 2. N. Maiorov i dr.; 3. K. Nekrasova i dr.; 4. K. Simonov, undated; 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS); sd. col.; 1/2 in. NTSC format (Box 78, Folder 127)
    Otrada, N.; Nekrasova, K.; Simonov, K.; Petrov, S.; Sokolov, V.; Sobol', M.; Temin, G.; Dombrovskii, Iu.; Kochetkov, A.; Kogan, P.; Kul'cheshchkii, M.; Maiorov, N.; Markov, S.
  - The Art of Peace (Length 28:50); Americans in USSR, Chernobyl, 1986; 1 videocassette of 1 (VHS); sd. col.; 1/2 in. NTSC format (Box 78, Folder 128)
  - Portrait of the Soviet Union Parts 1,2, 1988 Aug. 29; Videotape (Box 78.1, Folder 1)
    Host Roy Scheider. 2 hr.
    Scheider, Roy
  - Portrait of the Soviet Union Parts 3,4, 1988 Aug.; Videotape (Box 78.1, Folder 2)
  - Portrait of the Soviet Union Parts 5,6, 1988 Aug. 31; Videotape (Box 78.1, Folder 3)
  - Portrait of the Soviet Union Part 7: Final Episode, 1988 Sept. 1; Videotape (Box 78.1, Folder 4)
    Host Roy Scheider. 1 hr. Includes Frank Ashley's business card with a handwritten note to Yevtushenko on the back.
  - The American Poetry Archive: Yevgeny Yevtushenko, 1987; Videotape (Box 78.1, Folder 5)
  - The American Poetry Archive: Yevgeny Yevtushenko, 1987; Videotape (Box 78.1, Folder 6)
- Clippings, Series 9.
  Arrangement note
  The clippings are roughly arranged by country.
  From Russian and International newspapers about Yevtushenko.
  - English language press, 2000 Oct. -2002 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - English language press, 1965-2000 Jun. (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Russian language press, 2000 Sep.-2002 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Russian language press, 1991-2000 Jul. (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - German language press, 1962-2000 (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Spanish language press, 1998-2001 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Different languages press, 1997-2001 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Different languages press, 1997-2001 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - English Language Press [1 of 3], 1963 - 1972; Accession 2004-022 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - English Language Press [2 of 3], 1972 - 2001; Accession 2004-022 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - English Language Press [3 of 3], 1979; Accession 2004-022 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - Russian Language Press, 1967 - 2000; Accession 2004-022 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - USA Press [1 of 5], 1966 Nov.; Accession 2004-022; Copies of clippings (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - USA Press [2 of 5], 1966 Nov. - Dec.; Accession 2004-022; Copies of clippings (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - USA Press [3 of 5], 1966 Nov. - Dec.; Accession 2004-022; Copies of clippings (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - USA Press [4 of 5], 1966 Dec. 21 - 31; Accession 2004-022; Copies of clippings (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - USA Press [5 of 5], 1967 Jan.; Accession 2004-022; Copies of clippings (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - General Newsclippings, 1960s - 1980s; Accession 1999-231 (Box 108)
    Original box number 6.3
  - General Newsclippings, 1960s - 1980s; Accession 1999-231 (Box 109)
    Original box number 12.1
  - Foreign Clippings (Russia and England), Accession 1999-231 (Box 110)
    Original box number 12.2
  - Clippings (Italy), Accession 1999-231 (Box 111)
    Original box number 14.
  - Clippings (Germany), Accession 1999-231 (Box 112)
    Original box number 6.
  - Clippings (Russia), Accession 1999-231 (Box 113)
    Original box number 16
  - Clippings (Russia), 1960s - 1990s; Accession 1999-231; loose clippings and scrapbooks (Box 114)
    Original box number 19.1
  - Clippings (Russia, England and Italy), Accession 1999-231 (Box 115)
    Original box number 21.1
  - Clippings (Finland, Poland, Bulgaria, France, Yuogoslavia), Accession 1999-231 (Box 116)
    Original box number 21.2
  - Clippings (Russia, Israel), Accession 1999-231 (Box 117)
    Original box number 28.1
  - Clippings (Russia, Israel, America, Chile), Accession 1999-231 (Box 118)
    Original box number 28.2
  - Clippings (Spain, Latin America, Germany), Accession 1999-231 (Box 119)
    Original box number 29.2
  - Clippings (Spain, Latin America, Germany), Accession 1999-231 (Box 120)
    Original box number 30.1
  - Clippings (United States of America), Accession 1999-231 (Box 121)
    Original box number 30.2
  - Clippings (United States of America, Russia), Accession 1999-231; loose clippings and scrapbooks (Box 122)
    Original box number 31.2
  - Clippings (Russia), Accession 1999-231; loose clippings and scrapbooks (Box 123)
    Original box number 33.1
  - Clippings (Russia), Accession 1999-231 (Box 124)
    Original box number 33.2
  - Clippings (Russia), Accession 1999-231 (Box 125)
    Original box number 11
- Accession 2009-109 (Box 1 (2009-109))
  Scope and Contents
  video and audio materials, 1999-2000; notebook and artist's book; acquisition material, 1997; symposium on Russian cultural politics, 2006; correspondence, 2006; photo, 1972; and Burmese material.
- Accession 2011-071
  - Correspondence
    - Official Letters to Yevtushenko, A-R (1986-2010) (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Official Letters to Yevtushenko, S-W (2003-2010) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Official Letters from Yevtushenko, A- V (2002-2010) (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified Official letters. No last name or (and) n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Private Letters: A-L (1972-2010) (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Private Letters: M-T (2000-2010) (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Private Letters: No last name, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Family Correspondence: Aleksander, Anton, Yevgenii Yevtushenko [Yevtushenko's sons] (2003-2009) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Manuscripts
    - Poetry Drafts: A-P, Mostly untitled, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Poetry Drafts: R-Z, Mostly untitled, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Poetry Drafts: in English, Translations (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Poetry Drafts: Fragments, Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Notebook Drafts: Poetry (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Notebook Drafts: Notes, Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Handwritten texts: Drafts, notes, speeches (Untitled, n.d.) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Printed drafts: Essays, reviews, orbituaries (1995-2006) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts by others
    - Poems sent to Yevtushenko, A-M (1996-2011) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Poems sent to Yevtushenko, N-T (2000-2010) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Poems sent to Yevtushenko, unidentified (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Essays about Yevtushenko (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Writings on different subjects (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Performances and festivals, including invitations
    - Bulgaria (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Colombia (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Germany (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Great Britain (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Greece (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Israel (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Italy (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Macedonia (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mexico (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mexico, 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Romania (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Russia (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - San Salvador (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Ukraine (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - South Korea (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Venezuela (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - United States, California-New Mexico (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - United States, New York-Wisconsin (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Personal papers
    - Biographies of Yevtushenko (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Museum of Yevtushenko (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Course materials, Syllabus (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Librex Montale Prize, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Students' Works (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Residences (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Personal documents (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Financial documents (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Ceremony of Recognition in Yad Vashem, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Support of Nomination for the Nobel Prize in Literature, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - American-Russian Cultural Cooperation Foundation Award, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Honorary citizen of Madison, Wisconsin (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Associate Member of the Academy of American Poets, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Photographs (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Postcards to Yevtushenko (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Addresses (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Theater programs, tickets (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clippings
    - English Language Press, 1986-2009 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - English Language Press, 2000-2009 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Russian Language Press, 2000-2007 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Russian Language Press, 1986-2007 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Russian Language Press, 2007-2009 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Italian Press, 2006-2009 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Press: Different Languages, 2005-2010 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Information from Internet (Box 4, Folder 7)